STAFF SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Professional Summary

Forward-thinking Software Engineer with background working effectively in dynamic environments. Fluent in Java and Typescript programming languages used to develop software within Retail and Health care domains. Proud team player focused on achieving project objectives with speed and accuracy. Also experience leading teams with multiple initiatives and taking them to production.

Skills

- Agile, XP
- Angular, Sprint boot
- Java, Javascript, Typescript
- Oracle, Cassandra
- Cloud technologies
- Kafka, Elastic

Work History

08/2016 to Current

Staff Software Engineer Lockheed Martin Corporation â€" Meridian, MS

- 2 plus years of experience leading team, multiple projects and took them to dead line.
- Coordinate Financial validations with multiple teams involved and established financial approval so that feature can be rolled out to
- Work with UX team on technical feasibility's, and design consideration for intuitive user experience
- Consulted with Principal engineers on technical solutions for multiple features.
- Monitor and listen to application users feedback and bring issues up to Product Manager to prioritize it.
- Work with product manager regularly on quarterly planning meeting and align stories accordingly
- Lead and conduct dev huddles, technical design sessions for project initiatives
- Review peer code reviews and suggest periodic refactoring for code maintenance
- Responding to critical production support alerts and engaging operations in case of major outages. As well as clean up activity and
 participate in BPM's.
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans
- Led Order Up Delivery Major appliance, Order up Splits development initiative as Subject Matter Expert and primary point-of-contact for project management staff

07/2015 to 08/2016

Sr Software Enginner Apex Systems â€" Mission , KS

- Create Technical Design & Modeling using IBM Rational software architect
- Interact with business and other IT teams on production fixes . Change requests and monthly cycle releases
- Apply business logic using Java/J2EE technologies and implemented SOAP web service and exposed it to external source systems to invoke them.
- Implemented admin console web application for internal use purpose using JQuery, HTML and CSS
- Performed unit testing, component integration, smoke testing and load testing using SOAP UI.
- Coordinated for user acceptance testing (UAT) and fixed defects after UAT.
- · Deployed and tested applications using IBM urban code , Jenkins in WebSphere application server. Coordinated and lead deployment release cycles.
- Â: Performed up fitting all QA environments to latest release and maintaining lower environment applications health.
- Â: Implemented spring framework for CCM and EPS applications. Introduced dependency injection using spring framework.
- · Implemented **Spring JMS** integration for CCM and EPS (enterprise print solutions) applications
- Â: Lead **production deployments**, validated application health through **Splunk** dashboards, alerts, reports and field extractions.
- A Wrote basic **SQL** queries and operations/maintenance for this enterprise application in oracle 11g.
- Â Designed error reprocessing unit which increased productivity of application and more fail safe.
- Â: Basic working knowledge of EMC xPression 4.5 tools which is PDF, HTML type document generation tool.
- A: Interacted with business team for UAT testing, QA team for SIT/CIT testing and support/run team for production incidents and PBI.
- A Interacted with IT architects to check on applications health and performance improvements.
- · Redesigned CCM application with help of IT architects and decoupled application from single unit (web services, web application and MQ listeners) into multiple independent units (MDB, web services, web application)
- · Implemented **maven** build tool for CCM application.
- A. Wrote J-Unit test cases using **power mock** tool.
- · Helped Continuous integration for CCM application through maven, Jenkins and IBM urban code tools.
- · Learning to use tools like **JIRA**, **docker** and **bamboo** etc... for continuous integration\
- A Practicing **agile** methodology

08/2013 to 07/2015

IT Analyst Caci International Inc. – Kansas City , MO

Create Technical Design & Modeling using UML 2.0 and Microsoft Visio 2010

- Apply Business logic using Java Collections framework.
- **Designed and developed** solution to automate age old paper base **folder system** (managing orders manually and moving them from one folder to another using drop boxes at store) with application using Flex and Restful web services(with abstract factory design pattern) which own accolades from store business and operations team for its performance, maintainability and ease of use
- Performed **Data model** conversion from legacy Informix tables to sterling tables there by changing 20 year old home depot order system Informix tables to migrate to sterling product
- Worked with heterogeneous systems like Measure Comp, Tyler and numerous third party vendors for special orders in order to
 communicate order information to those systems there by integrating existing ordering system to different vendors for different types of
 orders.
- Performed impact analyses for existing clients who use special services application to ensure backward compatibility with new conversion there by ensuring minimal impact to all interacted systems.
- Developed components using restful web services using secure programming methodology standards
- Interacted with different teams including IBM Sterling, POS, external appliance systems, online systems e. t. c to convert orders to
 special services orders. Worked closely with payment systems of home depot like PTM, POS, and Show room POS to build interfaces
 for order tendering.
- Deployed and tested applications on **Tomcat web server** and Web sphere application server

10/2009 to 07/2013

Junior Java Developer TCS â€" City, STATE

- Used prepared statements and callable statements to implement batch insertions.
- Work with JAXB to develop export / Import Process for XML Based data.
- Creating Java, J2EE reusable business components and XML, XSL and XSD schema definitions.
- Creating **REST Web Services** to connect with external clients.
- Helped junior developer understand project specifics.
- Worked in SVN repository to commit and track code changes.
- Coordinating with functional team related to Design part & Keep Track of all changes.
- Used Microsoft Visio 2010 to draw and present business flow diagrams.
- Used **Spring MVC** framework (model â€" view â€" controller)
- Used **Java collections**, **generics** for applying business logic.

Education 05/2009

Bachelor of Technology: Computer Science

Pondicherry University - City